Finding Aid for Emil Lorch Papers 1891-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Architectural drawings
  - Michigan
    - Wayne County: Detroit
      - Fort Wayne (Folder 12)
Correspondence, reports, questionnaires, etc. of the A.C.S.A., 1915-1919, 1931-1932 and April 18, 1938
Baldwin, Frank Conger, 1869-1945.
October 18, 1910; also in Architectural League of America series
Barbour, Levi L. (Levi Lewis), 1840-1925.
December 1905 and March-May 1906 (regarding women's dormitories)
Belle Isle (Detroit, Mich.)
March 24, 1921, regarding the Belle Isle bridge
Booth, Henry Scripps, 1897-
February 17, 1937
Burnham, Daniel Hudson, 1846-1912.
May 9, 1908
Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.
December 8, 1920
Chandler, F. W. (Francis Ward), 1844-1926.
December 14, 1905, Jan. 10 and March 6, 1906 and December 2, 1909
Copeland, Royal S. (Royal Samuel), 1868-1938.
Correspondence, 1937. Jan 1938, and February 3, 1947 (mostly relating to the restoration of Gordon Hall in Dexter, Michigan)
Cret, Paul Philippe, 1876-1945.
Letter from PC to Edward C. Van Leyen, October 25, 1919
Crouse, John Robert, 1874-1946.
Correspondence, 1924-1926 and 1929-1936, almost entirely relating to the Waldenwoods project in Hartland, Michigan.
Detroit Edison Company
Material, 1912-1913, on the Ann Arbor and Ypsilanti locations of Detroit Edison buildings for which Lorch was the architect.
Detroit Museum of Art
Correspondence, programs, etc., 1895-1900, of the Detroit School of Art with which Lorch was associated.
Elmslie, George Grant, 1871-1952.
November 13?, 1905, Dec. 13, 1905, Dec. 15, 1905, Jan. 1906, February 12, 1906, Dec. 18, 1909 (to Barbara Lorch), Feb. 9, 1911 (to Francis Shenehon, Jan. 6, 1912 (to Minnie Lorch), July 8, 1913 (to W. B. Griffin), July 8, 1913 (to William L. Steele)
July 19, 1919, Oct. 14, 1919, March 20, 1920, April 14, 1920, October 13, 1920 (EL to GE on front), October 14, 1920 (GE to EL on reverse), October 14, 1920, undated 1920?
Jan. 24, 1921, Nov. 30, 1923, Dec. 31, 1924, Nov. 17, 1924, August 31, 1925, September 12, 1925, April 1, 1926?, September 15, 1926?, November 3, 1926
March 12, 1927, May 20, 1927, October 13, 1927, Dec. 22, 1927, Dec. 31, 1927 (to Minnie Lorch), June 13, 1929, September 1930 (to Connie Lorch), November 1930 (typewritten text of speech read before a meeting of the Illinois Society of Architects with handwritten annotation)
April 19, 1932 (to Connie Lorch ?, November 18, 1932, March 29, 1935, October 20, 1933, March 29, 1934, April 6, 1934, April 23, 1934, April 25, 1934, November 7, 1934
March 14, 1935, Spring Solstice 1935, March 6, 1935, April 4, 1936, March 18, 1936, March 23, 1936, March 28, 1936, July 10, 1936, October 27, 1936
Jan. 6, 1937, Feb. 26, 1937, April 16, 1937, Feb. 4, 1938, April 28, 1938 (GE to Architectural Forum), Sept. 28, 1938
March 24, 1941, May 2, 1941, May 18, 1942, August 13, 1943, Dec. 6, 1943, Dec. 31, 1943, August 14, 1944, Sept. 21, 1944, Sept. 25, 1944, Oct. 11, 1944
April 1945?, Jan. 14, 1946, Dec. 21, 1945, March 29, 1946, April 4, 1946, June 11, 1946, July 24, 1946, January 18, 1947, Feb. 1947 (EL to Charles D. Maginnis with annotations by GE), March 24, 1947, April 23, 1947, Dec. 4, 1947, Dec. 24, 1948, Jan. 1952
Fairbanks, Avard T. (Avard Tennyson), 1897-1987.
Letters, April 6, 1929, of Ellis F. Laurence commenting on Avard Fairbanks
Ferris, Woodbridge N., 1853-1928.
Letter, June 22, 1915
Fitzgerald, Frank Dwight, 1885-1939.
Letter, November 16, 1936
French, William M. R. (William Merchant Richardson), 1843-1914.
May 11, August 5, September 3, September 20, November 6-7, 1901, March 18, 1907, February 15, October 9, November 29, 1909
Gilbert, Cass, 1859-1934.
Letters, Feb. 15, 1909, November 22, 1909, June 26 and July 10, 1916
Gomberg, Moses, 1866-1947.
Letter, May 5, 1909
Goodhue, Bertram Grosvenor, 1869-1924.
May 11, 1923
Hamlin, Talbot, 1889-1956.
October 13, 1936 (to Mabel Randall), Nov. 4, 1936
Holland (Mich.)
Memo, Feb. 12, 1937, regarding the city.
Hutchins, Harry B. (Harry Burns), 1847-1930.
Letter, September 7, 1913
Ives, Percy, 1864-1928.
Letters, July 10 and 26, 1897, Feb. 20, April 7, April 22, August 1, September 13 and November 19, 1898, March 27, 1899, May 2, 1899, January 4, 1923.
James, Edmund J. (Edmund Janes), 1855-1925.
Letters, July 14, Aug. 6, 21 and 22, 1913
Jones, Roy D.
Correspondence, 1920s and 1930s
Kahn, Albert, 1869-1942.
Letter, November 27, 1898, Feb. 15, 1941
Kimball, Fiske, 1888-1955.
Letters, Sept. 12, Oct. 14, Nov. 29 and Dec. 29, 1916; and Mar. 3 and July 23, 1917
Laird, Warren Powers, 1861-1948.
Letters, Sept. 25, 1918 and undated 1918
Lawrence, William Henry, b. 1868.
Spring 1930
McKim, Charles Follen, 1847-1909.
Feb. 15, 1909
McKim, Mead & White.
Feb. 15, 1909
Marquand, Allan, 1853-1924.
July 12, 14 and 17, 1905
Maroti, Geza R.
Dec. 17, 1936, Feb. 8, April 14, 1937, Jan. 13 and Dec. 20, 1938
Mason, George D., b. 1856.
1900s
Michigan. State Board for Registration of Architects, Engineers, and Surveyors.
Papers, 1915-1917, and Jan. 1927; see especially March 1, 1915
Moon, Charles H.
Letter, Feb. 7, 1898
Mumford, Lewis, 1895-
Letter, March 7, 1928, concerning campus building
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.
Letter, Jan. 2, 1938
National Council of Architectural Registration Boards.
1937-1938; see especially Aug. 9, 1937 and June 25, 1938
Pond, Irving Kane, 1857-1939.
Nov. 30, 1909, October 25, 1919 (to Edward C. Van Leyen), May 11, 1923, Nov. 18, 1935, April 6, 1936
Pritchett, Henry Smith, 1857-1939.
June 25, 1901 and March 17, 1902
Rindge, Warren.
1930s
Robinson, John Beverly, 1853-1923.
1904-1912 and April 1915
Ross, Denman Waldo, 1853-1935.
May 11, May 21, Aug. 16, Aug. 21, Aug. 27, Oct. 21, 1901, April 15, June 29, 1902, March 12, 1906, Dec. 11, 1909, May 30, 1910, July 23, 1917, June 2, 1918
Saarinen Eliel, 1873-1950.
Letters, Dec. 7, 1923 and Oct. 28, 1928; also see memo of Dec. 7, 1935 regarding Saarinen's plan for the University of Michigan campus and Burton Tower
Sleeper, Albert E., 1862-1934.
August 15, 1919
Sullivan, Louis H., 1856-1924.
Dec. 27, 1919, April 7, 1920, May 4, 1920, June 21, 1920, October 14, 1920, May 11, 1923, Jan 21, 1924 Jan. 31, 1924 (to Mr. and Mrs. Pickerell); information about Sullivan found in letters, July 8, 1902, Nov. 14, 1921 (memo), April 16, 1924, June 13, 1929, Nov. 1930, May 1946, October 1946.
Tau Sigma Delta
Letter and memorandum re fraternity, June 2, 1939
University of Michigan--Buildings
Memo, Dec. 7, 1920, regarding building program; papers, 1921, 1922, 1924 and 1927, have information on the architecture building
University of Michigan. College of Architecture and Design.
Material throughout, especially memos, April 21, 1913 and July 29, 1931, regarding department's separation from college of engineering; history of college, April 29, 1936
University of Michigan--Dormitories
Correspondence, March-May 1906, concerning building dormitories for women at the University of Michigan.
University of Michigan. Library
Memo of T. W. Koch consisting of his plan for the library, May 16, 1912
University of Michigan. Senate.
Reports, etc. of the Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies, spring of 1927.
Waldenwoods
Correspondence, 1924-1926 and 1929-1936, with John R. Crouse almost entirely relating to the Waldenwoods project in Hartland, Michigan.
Wallenberg, Raoul.
Nov. 25, 1936
Warren, Herbert Langford, 1857-1917.
Nov. 1901, Nov.-Dec. 1903, Jan.-March 1904, Nov. 19 and Dec. 1905, Jan. and July 1906, Jan. 1907, Jan. 19, Feb., May and Dec. 1909, June 1910, Jan. March 1911, May and June 1911, Sept. 1913, May 1915, Oct. 1915
Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.
July 18 and Aug. 5, 1905
World War, 1914-1918
Material, September 1918 regarding students war-time training.
Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959.
Letters from EL to FLW: Nov. 9 and Dec. 8, 1922, Jan 10, July 27, Sept. 23, Oct. 16, Nov. 2, 1923, Nov. 13, 1924